Elliott Lockwood

Austin, TX 78704

(713) 562 – 6480 | lockwood721@gmail.com

GitHub: www.github.com/elock721 | Heroku: elliottjlockwood@herokuapp.com

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/elliottjlockwood

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a 4-year bachelor's degree and a background in oil and gas. Always referred to by coworkers as a hardworking, adaptable, exceptional team player. Effective at approaching every job task or challenge with a combination of creativity and my passion for problem solving.

Technical Skills

Front End: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, ReactJS, Responsive Design, Local Storage

Back End: MySQL, MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js), User Authentication

Deployment: Heroku, Github

Web Dev Projects

*To be completed August 2020

GitHub Repo: Deployed App:

• Short summary of project (1-2 lines)

• Your core responsibilities in project (1-2 lines)

Tools / languages used

Find My Fare July 2020

GitHub Repo: https://github.com/elock721/Project-2-Idea
Deployed App: https://find-my-fare.herokuapp.com/

Allows users in the Austin area to find their favorite food trucks

- Backend engineer & Github/Deployment lead
- Javascript, SQL/MySQL Workbench, CSS Grid, Google Maps API, Node JS, Heroku, Github

Fish Guide Friend June 2020

GitHub Repo: https://github.com/elock721/Fish-Guide-Friend
Deployed App: https://mcui1997.github.io/Fish-Guide-Friend/

- Allows you to find the highest rated fishing guides in a specific area
- UI Engineer responsible for creating user friendly interface
- HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, JSON, AJAX, APIs, Github

Experience

Floor Hand: Spencer Ogden

01/2019 - 04/2020

- Effectively operated various types of drilling equipment to maximize drilling efficiency for every client
- Coordinated with the drilling fluid's engineer to maintain the integrity of the drilling fluid weight & viscosity at all times
- Headed comprehensive pre job safety meetings to delegate tasks to appropriate parties and mitigate all job risks

Bar Back: Houston Hospitality

11/2016 - 12/2018

- Taught new hires all necessary roles & responsibilities for maintaining restaurant's maximum operational efficiency
- Constantly assessed liquor supply of bar to ensure restaurant never lost an opportunity to profit
- Discovered a more efficient way to restock the bar that saved the restaurant time and money

Floor Hand: Ensco Offshore 10/2013 – 06/2016

- Effectively operated various types of drilling equipment to maximize drilling efficiency for every client
- Coordinated with the drilling fluid's engineer to maintain the integrity of the drilling fluid weight & viscosity at all times
- Headed comprehensive pre job safety meetings to delegate tasks to appropriate parties and mitigate all job risks

Education

Full Stack Web Development Certificate: Univ. of Texas - Austin, TX

2020

Bachelor of General Studies in History: Univ. of Kansas - Lawrence, KS